<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mead.fm</title>
    <description>A blog about startups, the environment, sport, Buddhism, and probably some other things.</description>
    <link>http://samjamead.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://samjamead.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 22:42:40 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 22:42:40 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kobe Is The GOAT</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slamonline.com/the-magazine/features/kobe-bryant-interview-feature-slam/#IpXKcbHO710DJfFh.97&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an awesome post&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Eric Dyson for SLAM Magazine. TL;DR &amp;mdash; I agree with Michael!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/img/kobejordan.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Kobe Bryant is the greatest basketball player of all time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been watching basketball for a long, long time, and up until very recently, I was not a big fan of Kobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first game of basketball I ever watched live was the Knicks @ the Magic, which makes me a) a Magic fan, and by extension b) a Tracy McGrady fan. If you&#39;re a T-Mac fan there&#39;s no way you&#39;re a Kobe fan, especially not while Tracy is leading the league in scoring and crashing out of the playoffs in the first round every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/img/kobe2.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/img/kobemcgrady.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after T-Mac went all Knicks-Pistons-Hawks-Qingdao on us (oh how I wish the Spurs could have been the happy ending!) I still didn&#39;t come round to the Black Mamba in a hurry. He was too selfish, too cold, too &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; for me to be a fan. There&#39;s nothing &#39;underdog&#39; about him, so I wasn&#39;t going to be rooting for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet here I am... Writing a piece on how I think Kobe&#39;s the GOAT.

&lt;p&gt;Better than MJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that says it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qQYz0I5dE_A&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QCdQ5LtJBGg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slamonline.com/the-magazine/features/kobe-bryant-interview-feature-slam/#IpXKcbHO710DJfFh.97&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an awesome article&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Eric Dyson for SLAM Magazine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:28:31 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/kobegoat</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/kobegoat</guid>
        
        <category>basketball</category>
        
        <category>kobe</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>User Stories: Tignes, France</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally published over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://snowriderswa.blogspot.com.au/2016/04/tignes-france-as-snow-sure-as-it-gets.html&quot;&gt;Snowriders WA&lt;/a&gt;, the largest community of skiiers and snowboarders in WA!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tignes/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tignes&quot; title=&quot;Tignes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-tignes&quot;&gt;About Tignes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tignes (pronounced ‘teen’) is the second highest resort in Europe and forms one half of the gigantic Espace Killy ski area. The resort is actually split into five villages; Val Claret, Le Lac, Le Lavachet (some folks consider Lavachet part of Le Lac) Les Boisses, and Les Brevieres.  The four villages sit at various altitudes between 2300 and 1550 around the bottom of a huge bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original village sat lower in the valley, but was flooded by the construction of a hydro-electric dam in the 1950’s. The remains of the village are visible when the lake is drained for maintenance once every ten years! I have also heard rumours that you can scuba dive through the old village in the summer too…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole of Tignes ski area is accessible on one lift pass, with the option to upgrade your pass to access the neighbouring resort of Val d’Isère, the other half of Espace Killy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-there&quot;&gt;Getting There&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tignes is part of the Tarantaise — a large valley containing some of the most famous resorts in France, if not Europe. All of the resorts in the Tarantaise are extremely easy to get to and Tignes is no exception. At the eastern end of the valley floor the town of Bourg-Saint-Maurice is the gateway to the Espace Killy (as well as Paradiski and several other smaller resorts). Bourg is accessible via rail and road. We flew in to Geneva, and from there it was a 3 hour train journey through the Savoy region of France. Trains in France are generally quite cheap — for the two of us it cost about $60 total to get from Geneva to Bourg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tignes/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tignes&quot; title=&quot;Tignes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve reached Bourg it’s a €12 ($18) coach ride up the mountain, which takes between 30 minutes and an hour depending on which village you’re staying in — but if you easily get bus-sick like me, make sure you don’t take a bus that goes to Tignes via Val d’Isère! It’ll add at least an hour on to the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also fly to Chambray or Lyon and take trains from there — Chambray is closest and therefore has the shortest transfer time but is also the smallest airport (less choice for flight times and more expensive flights).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those coming to Tignes from the UK it’s possible to take the Eurostar train direct from London to Bourg-Saint-Maurice, although it’s quite expensive, and you can cut a lot of that cost by changing in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-ski-area&quot;&gt;The Ski Area&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve arrived in Tignes you’ll be spoilt for choice at where to ski first! It will be largely dependant on the village you’re staying in, and each village is served by one or two major chairlifts to take you up to the mid-altitude slopes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With over 35 lifts and over 70 trails, there are plenty of options for both skiers and snowboarders of all ability levels. For beginners there are several ‘ski tranquil’ areas with short lifts and gentle green runs to warm up for the steeper slopes. At the other end of the spectrum advanced riders can enjoy the ‘ski natural’ pistes: ungroomed pistes that offer somewhere between black run and off-piste skiing, while still patrolled by the pisteur-secouristes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tignes/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tignes&quot; title=&quot;Tignes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the large number of lifts available there are relatively few options for descents from the top of each chairlift. Tignes has a way of forcing you into one of many scenarios where from the top of a lift, the only options seem to be a blue run back to the lift you just got off of, or a red run to the next lift along the mountain. This doesn’t necessarily detract from the skiing but it does make sure you need to pay slightly closer attention to the piste map to ensure a varied day’s skiing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to it’s enormous altitude, much of the resort is open and exposed to the elements, however there is some excellent skiing on the lower slopes towards Les Breviaries (far right on the piste map!) with lots of interesting cliff formations, frozen waterfalls, and some excellent tree-skiing too. For the opposite of that, take Funiculaire Du Perce-Neige to the highest point in Tignes and some wide open skiing on the Grande Motte glacier, where you can even ski a few hours a day in the summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;snow-conditions&quot;&gt;Snow Conditions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, due to elevation Tignes is one of the most snow-sure resorts in the alps (and therefore one of the most popular!). The week we were there five out of six days were reset days, with the whole mountain offering fresh tracks and no sign of the previous day’s skiing! Unfortunately with that level of snow comes an equal amount of cloud, which can settle over the entire resort and make navigating a little tricky. On the days when visibility is almost at zero, bear in mind that in the piste markers on the right hand side of the piste all have orange tips (while the poles on the left don’t). When things get really bad, just make sure that you don’t ski between two poles with the same colour tops!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tignes/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tignes&quot; title=&quot;Tignes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course it only takes one day of bluebird conditions to completely forget that clouds ever existed. And because of the sheer size of the skiable area Tignes has to offer, usually it’s only a matter of heading up or down to get yourself out of the cloud and back into slightly more comfortable territory. Top tip: if the cloud hasn’t shifted by mid morning, get yourself down to Les Boisses and Les Brevieres for the best visibility on offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;timing-is-everything&quot;&gt;Timing Is Everything&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going skiing in Tignes early in the season is a fine line — usually there isn’t much snow to be had before Christmas, making Christmas, New Year and January your best bet for a combination of deep snow and empty lift lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any resort in the French Alps, it can be very difficult to find a quiet week skiing beyond January. In February and March, the whole of Europe seems to be on school holidays, which I could never get my head around until someone explained to me that in France and Italy, the school holidays for different regions are deliberately staggered to allow families a week in the mountains! What a marvellous example of European efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general the two main weeks to avoid are the Parisian holiday and the English half-term holiday — they change dates every year but a quick Google could save you a lot of time shuffling around in a queue for the chairlifts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;accommodation&quot;&gt;Accommodation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tignes has a huge variety of accomodation options, from fully catered private chalets to self catered apartments in the tower blocks that are so quintessentially Alpine. The best thing about Tignes accommodation is that whatever you choose, the slopes will be ultra accessible. A large proportion of the accomodation is ski in ski out, and for those places a little further from the slopes, there’s an excellent free shuttle bus service that winds it’s way up and down the villages to get you where you need to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;apres-ski&quot;&gt;Apres-Ski&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any resort in the Alps, the skiing is only half the story! The day is only really getting started when the last lift closes and there’s more often than not a huge group of people dancing around a DJ with his head out the roof of some Jeep / snowmobile hybrid at the rond point des pistes. Don’t worry about being put off either, these seemly impromptu dance parties are pretty family-friendly with the kids zipping around on toboggans while everyone else enjoys a vin-chaud or three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tignes/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tignes&quot; title=&quot;Tignes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re willing to stay out a bit later my advice is to find somewhere that the bartender is sitting on what seems like the wrong side of the bar, holding court to a bunch of his mates! These are the most authentic places going, and don’t worry, he will still be able to reach the beer taps from where he is! The relaxed attitude is typically French and in a place like that, you’ll automatically be started a tab, and you might even get a funny look if you try to pay after each round of drinks. That’s not necessarily true in a busy bar though. If in doubt, copy the locals!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;catering&quot;&gt;Catering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of the restaurants in the alps is enough reason alone for some folks to travel, and Tignes is no exception, so it’s definitely worth keeping some room in the budget for two or three meals out. To help balance the cost there’s at least one ‘Sherpa’ supermarket in each village. Some people will tell you that it can be expensive to shop up the mountain but I have never really found it to be the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At lunch you won’t be short of options for food up the mountain — and again following local habits is your best bet. The service is often not very good at some of the higher-end restaurants, and the food is often overpriced to go along with it. I much prefer to find a quieter lodge with a fire going, a self service buffet and a full sized bar! If you notice a pisteur-secouriste tucking into a little warming Genepy with his lunch that’s usually good sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite restaurant for lunch in Tignes is at the top of the Chaudannes chair lift. Plenty of room to hang up wet clothes for half an hour, huge plates of salad and chips, soups with more cheese than soup, and goblets of Leffe beer to wash it all down. Bliss!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All things considered it would be hard not to have a really amazing week’s skiing in Tignes. Combine bucket loads of snow, ski in ski out accomodation, the option to eat somewhere different for breakfast, lunch and dinner each day, and bars where you might even be allowed to pull your own pint — you’re surely onto a winner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite part of Tignes is actually the lowest village of Les Breviaries, which offers skiing through the trees and a smaller, more traditional atmosphere in the village. It’s also the smallest of the villages which means the pistes home at the end of the day are likely to be slightly quieter and in better condition than you mind find of the highways leading back to Val Claret and Le Lac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tignes/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tignes&quot; title=&quot;Tignes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bonus-five-top-tips-for-an-awesome-week-in-tignes&quot;&gt;Bonus! Five top tips for an awesome week in Tignes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the Espace Killy ski pass — some of the best skiing in the Espace Killy region is on the border between Tignes and Val d’Isere, so you can plan an awesome day hopping between the two as long as you have the full mountain pass.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swap a ski — leaving your skis lying around outside a restaurant at lunchtime is an easy way to lose your hire deposit (especially if you’re having lunch in town). To avoid having your skis pinched by an opportunistic voleur, just swap one ski with a mate and make sure you don’t leave the two pairs next to each other. No-one is going to steal an odd pair of skis!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the last lift — and have a few beers up the mountain before you come back down! Most restaurants you find on the mountain have a bar which can be an awesome place to grab a beer and enjoy an Alpine sunset. Bonus, you get the mountain to yourself on the way back down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the first lift — and have lunch early. Obviously if you’re making first tracks you’ll have at least one run to yourself before the rest of the crowds hit the slopes. Just make sure you don’t take a run straight back to town, or you’ll be right at the back of the queue! Keep skiing away from town to stay ahead of the masses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have an early lunch — By stopping for lunch around 11.30 you can be back on the hill by the back of midday: right as most folks are heading in for their lunch. Another well timed break at around 2.30 will make sure you miss the post-lunch rush and leave you rested enough to ski for the rest of the day. For some reason lots of folks head in early, which means some of the quietest skiing of the day is in the last hour before the lifts close.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:28:31 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/tignes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/tignes</guid>
        
        <category>reposts</category>
        
        <category>exploring</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three weeks roaming in Bali</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally published over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://uproute.co&quot;&gt;uproute.co&lt;/a&gt;, a sweet startup that I just happen to work for!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/nusalembongan/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nusa Lembongan&quot; title=&quot;Nusa Lembongan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Trip —&lt;/strong&gt; Three weeks in Bali with a big group of friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration —&lt;/strong&gt; 21 Nights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Origin —&lt;/strong&gt; Perth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type of Trip—&lt;/strong&gt; Beaches, eating, exploring on mopeds, surfing, scuba diving, accepting a Bintang every time one is offered, speaking Indonesian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Size—&lt;/strong&gt; 2 people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trip Dates and Average Temperature —&lt;/strong&gt; End of August / beginning of September. It was a little bit busy due to the Australian school holidays. I would go again in April or May. Lovely temperatures but quite humid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mode of Transportation —&lt;/strong&gt; Aeroplane&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arrival Logistics —&lt;/strong&gt; Landed at Denpasar airport, took a pre-arranged driver to our first night’s accomodation in Sanur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost per Person —&lt;/strong&gt; $1000 - $2000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Route —&lt;/strong&gt; One night in Sanur, boat to Nusa Lembongan, 12 nights there, boat back to Sanur, taxi to Amed, 4 nights in Amed, taxi to Ubud, 3 nights in Ubud, taxi to airport, home :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accommodation —&lt;/strong&gt; We booked the first night in an AirBnb. Thereafter it was all winging it! On Lembongan we ended up in another AirBnb for 3 nights, then an unexpected move to Big Fish dive school for 7 nights. In Amed, our dive school put us up with a local guy called Hans. Legend. And finally an AirBnb in Ubud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Food and Drink Highlights —&lt;/strong&gt; Warungs! The cheaper the better the food was. Bamboo Warung on Lembongan was the best but I’m not telling you exactly where it is… You’ll have to find it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essential Packing for this Trip —&lt;/strong&gt; Take half the clothes you think you’ll need; I found it so cheap and easy to have laundry done that you can halve the amount you need to lug around with no worries! At the last minute I decided not to take my surfboard which was a good call; I ended up renting boards that were better suited to the conditions than mine would have been anyway!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-experience&quot;&gt;Our Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fantastic trip.&lt;/strong&gt; We were there for three weeks and during that time a lot of our friends came and went to the same places; I think at one point there were 12 of us for dinner! It was really really easy to find accomodation, dinner, activities, tours, moped hire, etc. etc. without any forward planning, which made it ideal for a big group. You were able to stay near enough to each other to hang out, without having to spend 24 hours per day together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/nusalembongan/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nusa Lembongan&quot; title=&quot;Nusa Lembongan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning some of the language really transformed the trip for me. I felt like on many occasions it scored us some preferential treatment at lunch or dinner (never a bad thing!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waves were awesome and the diving was world class so I will definitely be going back at the beginning of the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/nusalembongan/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nusa Lembongan&quot; title=&quot;Nusa Lembongan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-bits&quot;&gt;Best Bits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surfing at Shipwrecks was awesome and one of the main reasons I wanted to go to Lembongan in the first place. Scuba diving in Ahmed was also amazing and I would definitely go back to dive there. Eating in warungs was brilliant. However I think my favourite thing was speaking Bahasa Indonesia, the locals just LOVED it if you made an effort. Super rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/nusalembongan/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nusa Lembongan&quot; title=&quot;Nusa Lembongan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;worst-bits&quot;&gt;Worst bits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The litter and general attitude towards littering are very saddening and quite shocking to see. Although I do understand that for some folks there, they have more important things to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general I was also a little embarrassed by other tourists; some were so rude and disrespectful to the locals, which was very sad. If I was going to go back I would try and go at the quietest time of the year to avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ratings&quot;&gt;Ratings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rate the overall trip —&lt;/strong&gt; 8/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rate the activity on your trip —&lt;/strong&gt; 9/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rate the ease of logistics —&lt;/strong&gt; 9/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value for money —&lt;/strong&gt; 8/10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-the-traveller&quot;&gt;About The Traveller&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gender &amp;amp; Age Range&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Male, 25 - 35&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m from &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Devon, UK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My favourite trip as of late &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Skiing in the French Alps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travelling Style &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Book the first night and wing it from there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I like to go on the following types of trips &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Adventure, 4x4, Beaches, Hiking, Surfing, Culture, Scuba Diving, Camping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s a dealbreaker when &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; There are kids or generators (or, horror… Both!) in the campsite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continent I know the best &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Australasia / Oceania&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/nusalembongan/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nusa Lembongan&quot; title=&quot;Nusa Lembongan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 00:28:31 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/nusalembongan</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/nusalembongan</guid>
        
        <category>reposts</category>
        
        <category>exploring</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The End of 2015 Adventure: Captain&#39;s Log</title>
        <description>&lt;ul class=&quot;list-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Esther, Appin, Sam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&amp;middot;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;27th Dec &#39;15 &amp;mdash; 3rd Jan &#39;16&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&amp;middot;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2320 kms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Day 1 &amp;mdash; Perth to Fitzgerald River National Park&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day1_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day begins by cleaning the house. At 10am Esther is hoovering up Appin&#39;s hair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally departed at 11.14am. Odometer 349,475.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left Perth via Highway 41 (long hill out and up into the hills - the old girl struggled). First stop after two hours at Brookton for Lunch. Crossroads town on Highway 40. Reminds me of Northcliffe. Continued on HWY 40 to Hyden. Shit town. Everything closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refuelled at Lake King. Literally a pub on a crossroads. Lake King to Fitzgerald River National Park (East) arriving at 8pm. All campgrounds full - good - we camped overlooking the inlet instead. Very beautiful. Dinner of gnocchi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Day 2 &amp;mdash; Fitzgerald River National Park to Margaret Cove (Stokes National Park)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day2_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start the day with a breakfast of poached pears and mascarpone. Delicious. Campsite proves to be even better in the light. Hiked up East Mount Barren. Appin unwell and had to turn back. Esther and I embarked on an ill-advised climb to the summit but survived with good photos. Swam at Miley&#39;s camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day2_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drove to Hopetoun but bottle shop closed. Town pleasant regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day2_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drove to Margaret Cove based on Vicky&#39;s excellent notes. Sam suffering with dreadful heartburn. Esther strong. Very, very hot day. Wonderful campsite as described by Walkley. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dinner of chili washed down with the last of the awful Nebbiolo. Fabulous night sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Day 3 &amp;mdash; Margaret Cove to Dunn Rock (Cape Le Grand National Park)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day3_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ventured down onto Dead Seal Beach at Margaret Cove. Spectacular beach with rolling swell breaking in shallow water. Throwing huge barrels. Extraordinarily hot; temperature measured at 42&amp;#176;c by the Bureau but we heard 45&amp;#176;c quoted over UHF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Departed due to stress (heat and wind). Would be all-time if 15&amp;#176; cooler. We will be back. Drove to Esperance and swam in a sheltered haven to the east of the town. Lunch in the shade. Appin resuscitated a thirsty dragonfly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ventured into town to resupply and then drove from Wylie Head to Cape Le Grand National Park along the beach. Stunning views of Bay of Isles. Dashed to Dunn Rock for sunset and set up camp. Superb dunes in the distance to the east.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day3_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of bugs after sunset, but none after an hour or so. Curry for dinner. Finally drank cold, cold beers. Esperance a nice town and Cape Le Grand has more than meets the eye. Map updated accordingly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Day 4 &amp;mdash; Dunn Rock to Thomas River (Cape Arid National Park)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day4_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day4_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rose at 6.40am. B&#39;s sleeping. Explored immediate vicinity &amp;mdash; wonderful place. Nice swim in crystal clear waters. Washed with sand. Wind coming from everywhere (tent and schwag filled with fine sand overnight). Finally the heat has broken and we&#39;re left with an overcast day. Sun still attempting to break through. It is Australia after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leisurely double breakfast then broke camp and drove to Cape Arid via Condingup to refuel. Cookies and cream ice cream. Jumpstarted a stranded local. Hilarious. Very scenic road east to Cape Arid. Found camp site at Thomas River. Friendly camp hosts. Still overcast, still windy. Lunched then walked Tagon cliff walk via Dolphin Cove and Little Tagon Cove. Gorgeous white beaches and turquoise water even without the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day4_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day4_4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day4_5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good 6km walk with epic skinny dip at Little T Cove on the return leg. Saw roos and a large monitor (racing horse goanna perhaps?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Day 5 &amp;mdash; Cape Arid National Park (New Years Eve!)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day5_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leisurely breakfast at camp &amp;mdash; weather still overcast and cool. Decided to strike out for Mt. Ragged via Balladonia &#39;Road&#39;. Advised to advise a responsible person of our plans. Did so. The track is notoriously boggy in wet conditions so after 20km with rain looming we turned back. We shall return... Headed back to Thomas River and hot-tobogganed along the beach to Arid Bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &quot;We will climb a mountain if it takes us all day&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;Rabbitson&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunched at the base of Mt. Arid and then struck out for the summit. Easy start, steepens. Summit at 15.40. Spectacular views to the West, South and East. Wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day5_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day5_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day5_4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glorious skinny dip at the southern end of Yokinup Bay (Jedacorrup Beach?) in the clearest water I have ever encountered. Returned to camp and greeted by Mairéad and Shane, great to have them with us to celebrate the end of the year! Commenced a long evening of festivities. Happy 2016...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Day 6 &amp;mdash; Cape Arid National Park (1st January 2016)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day6_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly not hungover and reasonably early start. Stars last night were amazing and gave hopes of a fine day today but no such luck; still overcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drove back down the beach to find a sheltered spot from the wind. Perfect little fun waves for bodysurfing and handplanes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day6_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day6_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love watching waves break from below (although water not quite as clear as before). Double session. Mairéad hungover but coping admirally! Down to meagre rations of half a cheese sandwich each for lunch! Water running low too, so returned to camp. No food or water there either. Napped, woke, dined. More cards, more shooting stars. No sign of the sun today but tomorrow is another day. 2016 off to an excellent start!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day6_4.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Day 7 &amp;mdash; Cape Arid National Park to Esperance to Perth&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day7_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early start to refill water at Condingup Tavern after breaking camp. Wonderful early breakfast - Esther has done us proud as breakfast chef. Entered Cape Le Grand NP and headed to lucky bay. Raining. Kangaroos on the beach; extremely picturesque bay &amp;mdash; just a shame that there is a sealed road to access!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day7_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rounded corner to Thistle Cove, and then again to Hellfire Cove &amp;mdash; perhaps the best of the lot! Swam in the rain in the clearest water of the trip. Clearer than the water from the tap. Glorious. GP action galore! Made difficult decision to return to Perth based on weather conditions. Left Cape Le Grand and drove to Esperance along the beach. Large pod of dolphins having a surf in perfect little dolphin waves!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;captains-log-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/captainslog/day7_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resupplied in Esperance and then departed via Great Ocean Road; big scenery. Drove most of the route under clearing skies with driving lights. Very little traffic. Wonderfully delicious dinner, Appin a tremendous dinner chef all week. Arrived in Perth 1am. Odometer 351,795. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:28:31 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/captainslog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/captainslog</guid>
        
        <category>captainslog</category>
        
        <category>trips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Beginner&#39;s Guide to Bahasa Indonesia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Selamat Datang panduan pemula untuk Bahasa Indonesia!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/bali1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mopeds and temples&quot; caption=&quot;A more Indonesian scene you&#39;d struggle to find&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have only been to Indonesia once, but I loved it. I’m supposed to be back there right now, but Mt. Rinjani and her subjects had other ideas… Anyway, my favourite part of the whole trip was speaking the language with the locals. Indonesian (or Bahasa Indonesia, literally &lt;em&gt;the language of Indonesia&lt;/em&gt;) is a pretty easy language to learn. Even for people who speak English as their first language!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my guide to getting the most out of learning Indonesian. I will tack my “If you’re only going to learn ten phrases then learn these ten” phrases at the end of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indonesians absolutely &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; foreigners speaking their language.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
It should go without saying, but a tiny effort in the language department goes an extraordinarily long way when you’re visiting &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; new country. This seems to be doubly true in Indonesia. Even by learning just a few little words and phrases, you can guarantee yourself better service, hospitality and respect if you show the locals a little respect by using their own tongue. Even if you only greet people in Bahasa, and say please and thank-you in Bahasa, that elevates you above 90% of the non-effort-making travelers passing through the country. Easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ll be wrong first time. That’s ok!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Don’t be put off if you learn a word or phrase, only to be corrected by a local. This seems to be more common in Indonesian than any other language I have dabbled with. More often than not, when I learn new a word from a book and try it out on a local, it’s met with a blank stare of incomprehension. Or, more likely, it’s met with a laugh and swift education of the correct phrase to use in that given situation. Much of what I have learned from a phrasebooks and Google seems to be slightly &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; for every day conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems to be par for the course when learning Bahasa Indonesia. In fact, it’s pretty common to learn a word, try it out, be corrected, and then try the correction on someone new, only to discover that you’re still ‘wrong’ in the ears of the person you’re now talking to! And repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Example: ‘Good morning’ in Bahasa is ‘Selamat Pagi’, which officially ends at 11am. After 11am, one should switch to ‘Good day’, or ‘Selamat Siang’. However, half the people you meet will tell you off for using Siang at 11.30, and will insist that one uses Pagi until midday. Even though they aren’t wearing a watch, and they likely don’t know the time anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason for the misunderstanding is that Bahasa Indonesia is most Indonesian’s second language. They’re more likely to speak the local language or dialect at home and with friends, and only use Bahasa when they’re doing business or shopping or something else involving strangers. For example, in Bali, most people speak Balinese at home, which is a complicated language for a foreigner to understand. That doesn’t mean we shouldn’t try!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On that note, learn a couple of words from the local language.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
And by that I mean learn a little bit of Bahasa Indonesia &lt;em&gt;plus&lt;/em&gt; a little bit of, say, Balinese, or Javanese, or whatever the most prevelent language or dialect is where you’re going. It might seem like extra effort, but even just learning ‘thank-you’ in the local language will earn you bonus brownie points in a restaurant or at your accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most pronunciation is phonetic, with a few notable exceptions.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
A few rules to go by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘c’ is always pronounced ‘ch’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roll your ‘r’s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vowels seem to change pronunciation a lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get the pronunciation wrong don’t worry, they’ll correct you! It’s the effort that counts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indonesians speak really really fast.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
If you don’t understand someone, ask them to slow down. All too often if you don’t catch what’s said first time, it will be repeated in English, which is no good for learning! So make sure you jump in quick with ‘tolong bicarra lagi pelan pelan’ (please say again slowly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if what &lt;em&gt;you’ve&lt;/em&gt; said isn’t understood first time, try saying it again as fast as you can. Don’t worry if your words mash together and you lose some accuracy in pronunciation — you’re more likely to be understood if you speak fast rather than correctly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lastly, call everyone sir or madam at the end of each sentence.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Use &lt;em&gt;Pak&lt;/em&gt; (sir) and &lt;em&gt;Ibu&lt;/em&gt; (ma’am) to address everyone you meet. You’ll seem courteous, polite, and culturally aware in the company of your hosts. Litter your conversation with lots of sirs and ma’ams for maximum effect!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###If you’re only going to learn ten phrases, learn these ten:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All of these translations are spelled phonetically - don’t use this for written comms! This guide is designed to be spoken only…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please may we speak in English [pak / ibu]?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Minta apakah kita bisa bicarra Bahasa Ingris [pak / ibu]?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sorry [sir / madam] I don’t speak Indonesian!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Ma’af [pak / ibu], saya tidak bisa bicarra Bahasa Indonesia!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May we have some lunch?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Minta kami makan siang? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;It’s good to say this when you enter a restaurant, as it isn’t always obvious as to why you’re there (most places offer other services too, such as laundry or accomdation). Switch out ‘siang’ for ‘pagi’ or ‘melam’ to ask for breakfast or dinner respectively. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two large Bintang’s, please!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Minta dua Bintang besa &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Same again, please!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Minta satu lagi! &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Literally ‘please may I have one again’, so if you want to order two of the same, use ‘minta dua lagi’, and so on.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I already have one thanks.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Suda punya terimah kasih. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;An easy and polite way to decline an unwanted offer of a bracelet, snorkelling trip, massage, etc.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please may I have 2 million Rupia using a visa card?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Minta dua juta Rupia munggunakan visa? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;This one is very useful at a money exchanger (you can sometimes get a better rate than at an ATM). &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See you later!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Sampai jumpa lagi &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Literally means ‘see you again’. &lt;strong&gt;Never say goodbye to anyone&lt;/strong&gt; — they’ll find it rude! &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May I bargain [sir / ma’am]?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Boleh saya tawar [pak / ibu]? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Great one to use at the start of a haggling session. Be aware that the person you’re dealing with might say ‘tidak!’ (no). Some things (like fuel) are fixed price and can’t be haggled over.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you&lt;/strong&gt; (in Balinese) &lt;br /&gt;
Sook-sa-moor &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;To which they’ll say ‘mo-ali’.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where are you staying?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Dimana anda tinggal? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Expect to be asked this all the time! Usually, this is just small talk, so it’s ok to say ‘Saya tinggal di sudut’ which means ‘I’m staying around the corner’. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thus concludes the beginners guide to Bahasa Indonesia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully that’s enough to get you started. Of course it’s also important to learn the numbers, and the basics of please, thank you, and the various hellos. But these are the phrases I have used most often and for some reason, phrasebooks for languages all around the world have a general reluctance to teach novice linguists anything of any actual use!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 05:20:31 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/bahasa-indonesia</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/bahasa-indonesia</guid>
        
        <category>language</category>
        
        <category>indonesian</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Isaac Asimov</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I could list Asimov quotes for days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To succeed, planning alone is insufficient. One must improvise as well.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Salvor Hardin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the book &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus quote! Also from &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Never let your sense of morals prevent you from doing what is right.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Salvor Hardin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which I particularly love, because it begs the question: “Are morals universal or relative?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To which the best answer I have heard so far is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Morality is simply one man’s way of justifying a personal view of what is right and wrong. It is the rightness or wrongness that is universal and thus transcends morality.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Simon MacFarlane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting side-story — “Are morals universal or relative?” was one of the original 29 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.saberr.com&quot;&gt;Saberr&lt;/a&gt; test questions! I always used to answer ‘universal’, but now I might have to answer differently…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 01:56:31 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/isaac-asimov</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/isaac-asimov</guid>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
        <category>asimov</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Never Read The Comments</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The gender gap in the tech scene is a hot topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m the 24-year-old CTO of a startup that just raised $2 million. I built all of my company’s tech by myself for the first two years we existed. But, apparently, if I’m on your tech team you should [re]evaluate your life. … And, in a world where Snapchat and Facebook were built in dorm rooms and attracted great engineering teams, I’m going to guess that having a boss in their 20s isn’t cause for serious life-questioning either. I’m going to go out on a limb and say that the real problem is that I’m a woman, and I don’t look like you want a CTO to look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am proud to be part of a female-led company. I am proud that no one questioned my cofounder’s ability to be our CEO. Women have come very far. But we’re not there yet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@saraheadler/never-read-the-comments-9cba93b5712a&quot;&gt;Read Sarah Adler’s post on Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 17:54:31 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/never-read-the-comments</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/never-read-the-comments</guid>
        
        <category>snippets</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In Praise of the AK-47</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: I had a professor in school who went on and on about how well the AK-47 was designed. He stressed that as designers we should be able to appreciate an object’s design on a purely aesthetic level. Do you agree?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Fuck no. Fuck him. Fuck the AK-47. Fuck all guns and the people who design them, but especially fuck Mikhail Kalashnikov, the designer of the AK-47.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://deardesignstudent.com/in-praise-of-the-ak-47-a24cc8a46c13&quot;&gt;Read Mike Monteiro’s post on Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quote from Mikhail Kalashnikov which might give some context when considering the rhetorical question at the end of the article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I’m proud of my invention, but I’m sad that it is used by terrorists … I would prefer to have invented a machine that people could use and that would help farmers with their work — for example a lawn mower.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 21:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/ak-47</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/ak-47</guid>
        
        <category>snippets</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Desert Island Disks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Desert Island Disks is a BBC Radio 4 programme that’s been running since the 40’s. From Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Guests are invited to imagine themselves cast away on a desert island, and to choose eight pieces of music, originally gramophone records, to take with them; discussion of their choices permits a review of their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I like best is that the presenter (Kirsty Young) doesn’t beat around the bush! She is straight down the line with all of her guests and you often see a side of someone famous that you didn’t imagine. She’s very good at making people seem human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, no particular order, the eight pieces of music I would take to a desert island, and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Neighborhood #1 (Tunnels) - Arcade Fire
My favourite song of all time. I remember being at an Arcade Fire gig with my Dad in Cardiff, around 2009 or 2010. I’d gone across from Uni in Southampton on the train. I got more and more nervous with each song they played that they weren’t going to play this track. They ended up playing it as the second encore. Of course they did. I love the sense of desperation in the story. That’s a running theme throughout several of my choices, for some reason I love songs with a sense of desperation or adversity in them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Heroes - David Bowie
This is my Dad’s favourite track and therefore an automatic inclusion on my list! Old Alan was easily the biggest influence on my musical tastes growing up and was very forgiving of a dodgy teenaged foray into rap and hiphop. Dad has a habit of falling in love with songs and playing them over and over until he can’t listen to them anymore, or at least, until they don’t work in the same way any more. However he’s always said that Heroes is immune to the curse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Hallelujah - Jeff Buckley
Heard this for the first time in a hotel room in Brisbane whilst listening to Triple J count down their Hottest 100 Of All Time (it clocked in at number three). Again, there’s a desperation, whatever your interpretation of the track. It’s also quite epic, in an acoustic kind of fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Home - Edward Sharp and the Magnetic Zeros&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###A Little Piece - The Jezebels&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Citizen Erased - Muse&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Exit Music For a Film - Radiohead&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve hit publish on this… Even though it isn’t finished. It’s actually really hard! First of all to narrow down all of the music in the world to just 8 tracks, and secondly to justify why they’ve made that list. Maybe I will come back and finish this one day. Maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 20:06:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/desert-island-disks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/desert-island-disks</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Can&#39;t Handle Salt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Why don’t whales, that live in salt water and have salt water pass through their mouths, die of thirst?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why doesn’t the fresh water in a marine mammal’s body flow out into the salt water that surrounds it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is that marine mammals and fish have a number of adaptations that allow them to conserve fresh water and excrete salt very effectively. It’s not the cod liver oil you want, it’s the cod’s liver. A liver that can filter the ocean must have other uses. If I had a cod’s liver I bet I could drink a keg of beer and piss turpentine. I could pour soy sauce in my miso soup and drink it with a spoon made of anchovies. &lt;em&gt;Oh, to have the liver of a seal!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@gutbloom/five-ways-humans-were-cheated-by-evolution-5a6533e60906&quot;&gt;Read Gutbloom’s post on Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 19:21:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/we-cant-handle-salt</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/we-cant-handle-salt</guid>
        
        <category>snippets</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
