<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sam J A Mead</title>
    <description>A blog about startups, coding, the environment, and sports.</description>
    <link>http://samjamead.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://samjamead.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 21:56:46 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 21:56:46 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Beginner&#39;s Guide to Bahasa Indonesia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Selamat Datang panduan pemula untuk Bahasa Indonesia!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have only been to Indonesia once, but I loved it. I’m supposed to be back there right now, but Mt. Rinjani and her subjects had other ideas… Anyway, my favourite part of the whole trip was speaking the language with the locals. Indonesian (or Bahasa Indonesia, literally &lt;em&gt;the language of Indonesia&lt;/em&gt;) is a pretty easy language to learn. Even for people who speak English at their first language!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/bali2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Balinese hospitality&quot; caption=&quot;Balinese hospitality&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, learning the right way is not quite so straight forward. More often than not if I learnt a word from a book and tried it out on a local, it was met with a blank stare of incomprehension. Or, more likely, it was met with a swift correction of the correct phrase to use in that given situation; much of what I learned from a phrasebook seemed to be slightly &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; for every day conversation. Actually sometimes I was even rude to someone, just by using words I had literally learned from the dictionary seconds earlier. Culture is a magical thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/bali1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mopeds and temples&quot; caption=&quot;A more Indonesian scene you&#39;d struggle to find&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what follows isn’t necessarily the same as you’d find in a guidebook or phrasebook, but it seemed to work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason for the misunderstanding is that Bahasa Indonesia is most Indonesian’s second language. They’re more likely to speak the local language or dialect at home and with friends, and only use Bahasa when they’re doing business or shopping or something else involving strangers. For example, in Bali, most people speak Balinese at home, which is an extremely complicated language for a foreigner to understand. Doesn’t mean we shouldn’t try! I have included a couple of Balinese words below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-beginners-guide-to-bahasa-indonesia-or-how-i-learned-the-magic-words-to-use-in-bali-to-get-a-smile-from-anyone&quot;&gt;A beginner’s guide to Bahasa Indonesia, or, how I learned the magic words to use in Bali to get a smile from anyone.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All of these translations are spelled phonetically - don’t use this for written comms! This guide is designed to be spoken only…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few rules to go by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘c’ is always pronounced ‘ch’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roll your ‘r’s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you get the pronunciation wrong don’t worry, they’ll correct you! It’s the effort that counts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello&lt;/strong&gt; — Depends on the time of day. See below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good morning&lt;/strong&gt; — Selamat pagi (use this up until 11am)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;Open to interpretation! Some folks seemed to think ‘pagi’ finishes at 11am, some folks said midday. Whatever.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good day&lt;/strong&gt; — Selamat siang (use this from 11am to 3pm)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good afternoon&lt;/strong&gt; — Selamat sore {sawrrey} (from 3pm to dark)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good evening&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Good night&lt;/strong&gt; — Selamat melam (after sunset)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Each of those can be shortened to a friendly greeting / farewell. Eg. a bright and cheerful ‘pagi!’ will suffice!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sorry [sir / madam] I don’t speak Indonesian!&lt;/strong&gt; — Ma’af [pak / ibu], saya tidak bisa bicharra Bahasa Indonesia!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you speak English?&lt;/strong&gt; — Apakah anda bisa bicharra Bahasa Ingris?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 05:20:31 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/bahasa-indonesia</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/bahasa-indonesia</guid>
        
        <category>language</category>
        
        <category>indonesian</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Isaac Asimov</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I could list Asimov quotes for days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To succeed, planning alone is insufficient. One must improvise as well.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Salvor Hardin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the book &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus quote! Also from &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Never let your sense of morals prevent you from doing what is right.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Salvor Hardin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which I particularly love, because it begs the question: “Are morals universal or relative?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To which the best answer I have heard so far is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Morality is simply one man’s way of justifying a personal view of what is right and wrong. It is the rightness or wrongness that is universal and thus transcends morality.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Simon MacFarlane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting side-story — “Are morals universal or relative?” was one of the original 29 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.saberr.com&quot;&gt;Saberr&lt;/a&gt; test questions! I always used to answer ‘universal’, but now I might have to answer differently…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 01:56:31 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/isaac-asimov</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/isaac-asimov</guid>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
        <category>asimov</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Never Read The Comments</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m the 24-year-old CTO of a startup that just raised $2 million. I built all of my company’s tech by myself for the first two years we existed. But, apparently, if I’m on your tech team you should [re]evaluate your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[…]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, in a world where Snapchat and Facebook were built in dorm rooms and attracted great engineering teams, I’m going to guess that having a boss in their 20s isn’t cause for serious life-questioning either. I’m going to go out on a limb and say that the real problem is that I’m a woman, and I don’t look like you want a CTO to look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[…]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am proud to be part of a female-led company. I am proud that no one questioned my cofounder’s ability to be our CEO. Women have come very far. But we’re not there yet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@saraheadler/never-read-the-comments-9cba93b5712a&quot;&gt;Read Sarah Adler’s post on Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 17:54:31 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/never-read-the-comments</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/never-read-the-comments</guid>
        
        <category>snippets</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Foundation by Isaac Asimov</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I tend to get quite addicted to books very easily. Once I start reading a book that I like, it is extremely difficult for me to put it down. Queue several late night page-smashing missions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 05:14:31 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/asimov-foundation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/asimov-foundation</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>asimov</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In Praise of the AK-47</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: I had a professor in school who went on and on about how well the AK-47 was designed. He stressed that as designers we should be able to appreciate an object’s design on a purely aesthetic level. Do you agree?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Fuck no. Fuck him. Fuck the AK-47. Fuck all guns and the people who design them, but especially fuck Mikhail Kalashnikov, the designer of the AK-47.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://deardesignstudent.com/in-praise-of-the-ak-47-a24cc8a46c13&quot;&gt;Read Mike Monteiro’s post on Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two quotes from Mikhail Kalashnikov which might give some context when considering the rhetorical question at the end of the article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I’m proud of my invention, but I’m sad that it is used by terrorists … I would prefer to have invented a machine that people could use and that would help farmers with their work — for example a lawn mower.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Blame the Nazi Germans for making me become a gun designer … I always wanted to construct agriculture machinery.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 21:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/ak-47</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/ak-47</guid>
        
        <category>snippets</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Desert Island Disks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Desert Island Disks is a BBC Radio 4 programme that’s been running since the 40’s. From Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Guests are invited to imagine themselves cast away on a desert island, and to choose eight pieces of music, originally gramophone records, to take with them; discussion of their choices permits a review of their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I like best is that the presenter (Kirsty Young) doesn’t beat around the bush! She is straight down the line with all of her guests and you often see a side of someone famous that you didn’t imagine. She’s very good at making people seem human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, no particular order, the eight pieces of music I would take to a desert island, and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;neighborhood-1-tunnels---arcade-fire&quot;&gt;Neighborhood #1 (Tunnels) - Arcade Fire&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite song of all time. I remember being at an Arcade Fire gig in Cardiff, around 2008 or 2009, and I got more and more nervous with each song they played that they weren’t going to play this track. They ended up playing it in the encore, of course they did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the sense of desperation in the story. That’s a running theme throughout several of my choices, for some reason I love songs with a sense of desperation or adversity in them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heroes---david-bowie&quot;&gt;Heroes - David Bowie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my Dad’s favourite track and therefore an automatic inclusion on my list! Old Alan was easily the biggest influence on my musical tastes growing up and was very forgiving of a dodgy teenaged foray into rap and hiphop. Dad has a habit of falling in love with songs and playing them over and over until he can’t listen to them anymore, or at least, until they don’t work in the same way any more. However he’s always said that Heroes is immune to the curse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hallelujah---jeff-buckley&quot;&gt;Hallelujah - Jeff Buckley&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heard this for the first time in a hotel room in Brisbane whilst listening to Triple J count down their Hottest 100 Of All Time (it clocked in at number three). Again, theres a desperation, whatever your interpretation of the track. It’s also quite epic, in an acoustic kind of fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;home---edward-sharp-and-the-magnetic-zeros&quot;&gt;Home - Edward Sharp and the Magnetic Zeros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-little-piece---the-jezebels&quot;&gt;A Little Piece - The Jezebels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citizen-erased---muse&quot;&gt;Citizen Erased - Muse&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exit-music-for-a-film---radiohead&quot;&gt;Exit Music For a Film - Radiohead&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 20:06:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/desert-island-disks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/desert-island-disks</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Can&#39;t Handle Salt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Why don’t whales, that live in salt water and have salt water pass through their mouths, die of thirst?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why doesn’t the fresh water in a marine mammal’s body flow out into the salt water that surrounds it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is that marine mammals and fish have a number of adaptations that allow them to conserve fresh water and excrete salt very effectively. It’s not the cod liver oil you want, it’s the cod’s liver. A liver that can filter the ocean must have other uses. If I had a cod’s liver I bet I could drink a keg of beer and piss turpentine. I could pour soy sauce in my miso soup and drink it with a spoon made of anchovies. &lt;em&gt;Oh, to have the liver of a seal!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@gutbloom/five-ways-humans-were-cheated-by-evolution-5a6533e60906&quot;&gt;Read Gutbloom’s post on Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 19:21:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/we-cant-handle-salt</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/we-cant-handle-salt</guid>
        
        <category>snippets</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Revolt Against The Desk</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many writers maintain a private writing hut. The hut has one purpose: it’s the place they go to write. They don’t do anything else there. Once they can’t write any more, they go do something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s treat our desks the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mijustin/things-ive-quit-doing-at-my-desk-b9cfd73d44e7&quot;&gt;Read Justin Jackson’s post on Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1240/1*0tUbUaSSeT5KTKLHyCjbfQ.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;A private writers hut&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 50%; display: block; margin: 20px 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo: Ralph Morse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus!&lt;/strong&gt; Here’s something else awesome from Justin Jackson: &lt;a href=&quot;http://justinjackson.ca/words.html&quot;&gt;Words&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 21:48:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/revolt-against-desks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/revolt-against-desks</guid>
        
        <category>snippets</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Geniuses And Lovers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“It is very painful, I think, to be told: ‘You enchanted the world for me, you made me feel things I never knew I could, now please be normal at dinner.’ We are always saying this to people in one way or another, of course; maybe we have to.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@annie_frankly/be-normal-at-dinner-on-geniuses-lovers-and-the-asks-we-make-of-both-ecbe29b02f35&quot;&gt;Read Annie Frankly’s post on Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 00:11:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/on-geniuses-and-lovers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/on-geniuses-and-lovers</guid>
        
        <category>snippets</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Lean Convert, or, Taking Lean to its Logical Conclusion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a long time I went around telling people how I didn’t really believe in lean. I was pretty proud of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, I just didn’t understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t either, and that’s the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being lean isn’t the same as bootstrapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being lean doesn’t mean you build a prototype and throw it out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being lean doesn’t mean you continually iterate your features until you find product market fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ashley Aitken helped me understand!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving my startup helped me understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running a program helped me understand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 21:27:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://samjamead.com/blog/lean-convert</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://samjamead.com/blog/lean-convert</guid>
        
        <category>startups</category>
        
        <category>lean</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
